Guide to the Edward Vitale violin music collection, ca. 1700-1900
George Mason University Libraries
Special Collections and Archives, George Mason University
Edward Vitale violin music collection
ca. 1700-1900
George Mason University. Special Collections and Archives.
Edward Vitale
C0155
10 linear feet (26 boxes)
This collection contains manuscripts and published arrangements of 18th and 19th century violin music.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Collection donated by Christopher Thaiss in 1981.
Biographical Information
Edward Vitale was a symphony violinist.
Scope and Content
This collection contains manuscripts and published arrangements of 18th and 19th century violin music.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged by subject.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Special Collections and Archives holds other music collections including and the.
Index Terms
Persons:
Thaiss, Christopher J., 1948-
Subjects:
Violin music--19th century.; Violin music--20th century.; Violin and piano music.; Violin and viola music.
Contents List
- An electronic box inventory is unavailable. Please contact speccoll@gmu.edu for more information.
  - List of Instruments, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Carl Fischer's music library No. 114 Hrimaly scale studies for violin, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Flesch il sistema delle scale per violino, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Collection Litolff No. 1409 Louis Scherbert violin school Vol. 3, 1882 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Collection Litolff No. 1411 Louis Scherbert violin school Vol. 5, 1882 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Leopold Auer graded course of violin playing Book 8, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Carl Fischer's music library No. 358 F. Hermann violin school Vol. 1, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Carl Fischer's music library No. 502 Hans-Sitt Op. 92 Technical Studies Part 1: Exercises and studies for the cultivation of the left hand, Book 3 double stopping for the violin, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Violin exercises (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Carl Fischer's music library edition No. 638 O. Sevcik Op. 7 preparatory trill studies for the violin, part II, 1911; 1
  - Schirmer's scholastic series Vol. 40 One hour's daily exercises for the violin by Efrem Zimbalist, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Franz Kneisel advanced exercises for the violin, part 1, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Polo trenta studi a corde doppie per violino, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Carl Fischer's music library edition No. 112 Hans Sitt Op. 32 studies for the violin book III, 1899 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Edition Peters No. 3368 Wieniawski L'ecole moderne Op. 10 Sitt, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Violino 2 Etudes melodiques et progressives de F. Mazas pour violon avec accompagnement d'un second violon par Ad. Grunwald, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Edition Peters No. 2564 Vieuxtemps Konzert-etuden Op. 16, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Schirmer's Library Vol. 185 H. Wieniawski Op. 18 Etudes-caprices for violin (Lichtenberg) book II, 1903 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Kistner Edition No. 38 Lipinski 3 Capricci Op. 10 [Richard Hofmann] violin solo, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Edition Peters No. 1078 Dancla etudes Op. 68, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Carl Fischer's music library edition No. 110 Hans Sitt Op. 32 studies for the violin, book1, 1899 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Collection Litolff No. 1127 A. Rolla 10 etudes en duos pour 2 violons Op. 10 (A. Schulz), undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Collection Litolff No. 1126 A. Rolla 3 duos concertants pour 2 violons Op. 3 (A. Schulz), undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Carl Fischer's music library No. 251 J. W. Kalliwoda Op. 181 three duos concertants for two violins, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Collection Litolff 50 lecons pour 2 violons par Jos. Von Blumenthal, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Edition Peters No. 1988 Melodien-album - Operatic Melodies fur 2 violinen (Hermann), undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Collection Litolff No. 696 Opera-Album - Operatic Melodies 2 violinen (Dr. W. Volckmar), undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Collection Litolff No. 697 Opern-Album Beliebte Melodien (Melodies d'Operas - Operatic Melodies) 2 Violinen (Dr. W. Volckmar), undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Schiermer's Library Vol. 518 Viotti duets for two violins, book 1 Op. 29 (Lichtenberg), 1900 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Collection Litolff No. 2309 Boccherini 3 duos pour 2 violons (M. Dello), undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Carl Fischer's music library No. 251 J. W. Kalliwoda Op. 181 three duos concertants for two violins, 1904 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Violin-Konzerte Joh. Seb. Bach fur pianoforte u. violine herausgegeben von Gustav Schreck violinstimme bizeichnet von Andreas Moser No. 1 Konzert Amoll No. 2 Konzert Edur No. 3 Konzert fur 2 violinen D moll, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Collection Litolff No. 835 Pleyel 6 duos pour 2 violons Op. 23 (A. Schulz), undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Edition Peters No. 1776a. and b. Mendelssohn Lieder ohne Worte romances sans paroles Zwei Violinen (Wolff), undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Collection Litolff No. 838 P. Rode 6 duos pour 2 violons Op. 18 Cah. 2 (No. 4-6) (A. Schulz), undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Ludwig Spohr 50 ubungen und vortragsstucke aus der violinschule Fur Unterricht und praktischen Gebrauch eingerichtet von Friedrich Hermann Heft 1, No. 1-24; Heft II, No. 25-38; Heft III, No. 39-50, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Duos pour deux violons. Revus et doigtes par A. Blumenstengel, Ad. Grunwald, A. Schulz, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Twelve Melodic Recreations Op. 187 by Chas. Dancla, 1905 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Collection Litolff No. 695 Volkslieder fur 2 violinen (Dr. W. Volckmar), undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Duos faciles et progressifs pour deux violons par Charles Dancla, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Collection Litolff No. 1361 G. Zanger 10 kleine charakteristische tonstucke Op. 18 2 violinen, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Collection Litolff No. 1028 Louis Schubert violin-duette classischer stucke Cah. 5 Franz Schubert, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Collection Litolff Duos faciles et progressifs pour deux violons d'apries les grands maitres par Louis Schubert 4me Suite Felix Mendelssohn-Bartholdy Violin 1, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Collection Litolff Duos faciles et progressifs pour deux violons d'apries les grands maitres par Louis Schubert 4me Suite Felix Mendelssohn-Bartholdy Violin 2, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Twenty classic violin duets (first position) edited and arranged by Pasquale Tucciarone Op. 49, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Collection Litolff Duos faciles et progressifs pour deux violons d'apries les grands maitres par Louis Schubert 7me Suite C. M. von Weber, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - No. 1 Einleitung, Gebet und Ariette (Introduction, Priere et Ariette) aus Freischutz Violon2, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Carl Fischer's Music Library No. 741 Pleyel (Op. posth) three grand duos for two violins (J. Centano), undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Collection Litolff No. 1148 mazas 12 petits duos pour deux violons Op. 38 Cah. 1 (Nos. 1-6), undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Edition Peters No. 2685 Klassische stucke fur 2 violinen, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Violino 1 Collection Litolff Album klassischer stucke in progressiver folge fur den vortrang genau bezeichnet und bearbeitet von Ad. Grunwald, undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Violino 2 Collection Litolff Album klassischer stucke in progressiver folge fur den vortrang genau bezeichnet und bearbeitet von Ad. Grunwald, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Collection Litolff No. 1029 Louis Schubert violin-duette classischer stucke Cah. 6 Fr. Chopin, undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Collection Litolff No. 1158 F. Mazas L'ecole du violoniste deuxieme degre six duos concertants pour deux violons Op. 71 Cah. I [Ad. Grunwald], undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - A. Rolla drei duos violine und violoncello (Stutschewsky) III, undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Edition Peters No. 2105 Kalliwoda duos fur violine und viola Opus 208, undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Edition Peters No. 1414 Mozart duos fur violine und viola (Hermann), undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Collection Litolff No. 608 Mozart 2 duos pour violon et alto (A. Schulz), undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Collection Litolff No. 1188 violon - terzelle von Ad. Grunwald Heft 4, undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Collection Litolff No. 65 Beethoven Streich Trios Violino, undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Collection Litolff No. 65 Beethoven Streich Trios Acordes, undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Collection Litolff No. 65 Beethoven Streich Trios Acordes Violonocello, undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Six sonates pour violon seul Eugene Ysaye Op. 27, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Volkausgabe Breikopf unt Hartel No. 1171 Campagnoli Divertissemente fur Violine Op. 18 (J. N. Raunch), undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - J. S. Bach 6 suites sonatas for violincell arranged for violin by J. Ebner, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Fritz Kreisler three cadenzas to the Beethoven concerto for violin, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Universal-Edition No. 69 Hellmesberger Sr. Sechs Cadenzen, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Edition Peters No. 2594 Mazas 8 melodies pour violon, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Schirmer's Library Vol. 356 viewxtemps ballade et polonaise de concert Op. 38 (violin and piano) (Schradieck), 1895 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Carl Fischer's Music Library edition No. 376 F. David Op. 5 Je suis, 1896 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Violin music Lullaby by Max Reger Op. 79, No. 1 edited by Sam Franko, 1917 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Schirmer's Library Vol. 613 Masterpieces of the violin Vol. 18 H. Wieniawski Op. 16 Scherzo-Tarentelle for violin and piano (L. Lichtenberg), 1900 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Schirmer's Library Vol. 646 Masterpieces for the Violin Vol. 21 H. Weiniawski Op. 20 Fantasy Faust Opera by Gounod Violin and Piano (Lichtenberg), 1901 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Schirmer's Library Vol. 237 Masterpeices For the Violin Vol. 26 David Op. 16 Andante and Scherzo Capriccioso Violin and Piano (Schradieck), 1901 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Carl Fischer's Music Library Edition No. 87 H. Vieuxtemps Op. 35 Fantasia Appassionata for Violin and Piano, 1901 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Rudolf Friml Two Pieces for Violin and Piano Op. 59 Mignonette (Rezeda), 1909 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Edition Peters No. 1099a. Tartini 3 Sonaten (hermann), undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Carl Fischer's Music Library No. 64 Ch. De Beroit Op. 100 Scene de Ballet Fantasia for Violin and Piano, 1912 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - C. Fischer's Edition No. 64 Ch. De Beriot Op 100 Scene de Ballet Piano and Violin, 1896 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Schirmer's Library Vol 607 Master-Pieces for the Violin Vol 12 H. Wieniawski Op. 4 Polonaise Brillante for Violin and Piano (L. Lichtenberg), 1900 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Schirmer's Library Vol 218 H. Vieuxtemps Op 11 Fantaisie-Caprice for Violin Edition for Violin and Piano (Schradieck), 1900 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Carl Fischer's Music Library No. 644 Sarasate Op 24 Caprice Basque for Violin and Piano, 1911 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Schirmer's Library Vol. 1236 LALO op 21 Symphonie Espagnole for Violin and Piano (Lichtenberg), 1915 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Carl Fischer's Music Library Edition No. 387 H. Vieuxtemps Op 31 Concerto No. 4 (D Minor) for Violin and Piano (August Wilhelmj), 1910 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Schirmer's Library Vol 951 Wieniawski Op 22 Second Concerto in D Minor for Violin and Piano (Lichtenberg), 1909 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Schirmer's Library Vol 781 Ch de Beriot Op 16 Concerto No 1 for Violin Edition for Violin and Piano (Schradieck), 1903 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Toscha Seidel Eili Eili Traditional Yiddish Melody transcribed for Violin Piano, 1918 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - The Kneisel Collection for Violin and Piano Selections from the Masters Old and New Edited by Franz Kneisel Volume 1-3, 1918 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - The Kneisel Collection for Violin and Piano Selections from the Masters Old and New Edited by Franz Kneisel Volume 1-3, 1918 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Carl Fischer's Music Library No 125 Chas. Dancla Op. 89 Six Airs Varies for Violin and Piano, undated (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Vivaldi - Kreisler Concerto in C Major Violin and Piano, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Schirmer's Library Vol. 217 Bruch Op. 26 Concerto for Violin (Schradieck) Editions for Violin and Piano, 1900 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Edition Peters No. 1100 a. Viotti Violin-Concert No. 22 A moll - La mineur - A minor (Hermann), undated (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Carl Fischer's Music Library Edition No. 272 E. Grieg Op. 46 Peer Gynt Suite 1 for Violin and Piano, 1911 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Violinists Recital Album A Collection of 18 Famous Compositions for Violin with Piano Accompaniment Edited and Revised by Otto K. Schill and others, 1905 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - The Kneisal Collection for Violin and Piano Selections From the Masters Old and New by Franz Kneisel Volume 1-3, 1908 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Fritz Kreisler Transcriptions for Violin and Piano Ignace J. Paderewski Menuet, 1917 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Schirmer's Library Vol. 388 Louis Spohr Concerto 7 for the Violin Op. 38 (Violin and Piano) (Schradieck), 1896 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Carl Fischer's Music Library No. 539 B. Godard Op. 35 Concerto Romantique for Violin and Piano (Edith L. Winn), 1908 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - As played by Jascha Heifetz Joseph Achron Transcriptions for Violin and Piano Felix Mendelssohn - Bartholdy Op. 34 No. 2 On Wings of Song, 1919 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Schirmer's Library Vol. 216 Ch. De Beriot Op. 76 Concerto No. 7 for Violin Edition for Violin and Piano (Schradieck), 1900 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Schirmer's Library Vol. 360 Louis Spohr Concerto 9 for the Violin Op. 55 (Violin and Piano) (Schradieck), 1895 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Universal Edition No. 3720 Gluck-Manen Ballet Violino e Piano, 1912 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Fritz Kreisler Compositions for Violin and Piano 8. La Gitana (Arabo-Spanish Gypsy Song of the 18th Century), 1917 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Fritz Kreisler Works for Violin and Piano Original Compositions 6. Rondino (on a Theme by Beethoven), 1915 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Fritz Kreisler Violin Compositions Gypsy Caprice, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - A Stirring Song for Sunday School Rallies, Evangelistic Campaigns, Christian Endeavor Meetings, Etc., Etc. March on O Christian Warriors! Words and Music by J. Albanus Seablom Octavo Series No. 1, 1915 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Carl Fischer's Music Library Edition No. 301 Franz Ries Op. 34 Suite No. 3 (G Major) Moderato. Bouree. Adagio. Gondoliera. Perpetuum Mobile. For Violin with Piano Accompaniment, 1901 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Solo Repertoire Original Works and Arrangements for Violin and Piano Series 3 La Capricieuse, Op. 17 (S 3862) Edward Elgar, 1928 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - From the Repertoire of Efrem Zimbalist 3 Hebrew Melody by Joseph Achron, 1918 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Violin and Piano Leopold Auer Concert Transcriptions 4. The Lark (L'Aloutte) Romance (Glinka-Balakireff), 1919 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Violin and Piano Leopold Auer Concert Transcriptions 3. Andante Cantabile (from Tschaikowski's String Quartet Op. 11), 1918 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Violin and Piano Leopold Auer 6. The Walnut Tree (Der Nussbaun) (Robert Schumann), 1919 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Willy Burmester Pieces by Old Masters for Violin and Piano Volume 2, 1906 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Modern Concert Solos for Violin with Piano Franz Schubert Ave Maria (Transcription by A. Wilhelmj), 1909 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Fritz Kreisler Classical Manuscripts Violin and Piano No. 1 Liebesfrued' 2 Liebesleid, 1910 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Fritz Kreisler Classical Manuscripts Violin and Piano 12. Alt Wiener Tranzweiser: No. 3 Schon Rosmarin, 1910 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Violin Music From the Canebreak for Fiddle with Piano by Samuel Gardner Opus 5, No. 1, 1918 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Masterpieces for Violin and Piano Series 6 Dreams of Love (Liebestraume) Notturno No. 3 - Franz Liszt, 1904 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Cyril Scott Lotus Land Transcribed for the Violin and Piano by Frtiz Kreisler Opus 47 No. 1, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Fritz Kreisler Transcriptions for Violin and Piano Ignace J. Paderewski Menuet, 1917 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Recital Music for Violin and Piano Series 2 M. Moszkowski Serenata Op. 15 No. 1, undated (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Carl Fischer's Music Library No. 870 Wieniawski Op. 7 Capriccio-Valse for Violin and Piano (Leop. Auer), 1921 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Carl Fischer's Music Library No. 346 Hans Sitt Scale Studies Appendix to H. Schradieck's Scales for Violin, 1903 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Carl Fischer's Music Library Edition No. 84 Introduction and Rondo Capriccioso for Violin and Piano, 1897 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Carl Fischer's Music Library Edition No. 583 P. Rode 24 Caprices inform of Etudes for the Violin (Edmund Singer), 1905 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Carl Fischer's Music Library No. 875 Hundel Sonata No. 4 (in D) Violin and Piano (L. Auer and Carl Friedberg), 1919 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Carl Fischer's Music Library No. 568 G. F. Handel Sonata No. 1 in A for Violin and Piano (Musin-Gevaert), 1909 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Carl Fischer's Music Library Edition No. 384 Chas. Dancla Op. 73 Twenty Brilliant and Characteristics Studies for Violin, 1905 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Masterpieces for Violin and Piano Series 6 Reverie Op. 22 No. 3 H. Vieuxtemps, undated (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Masterpieces for Violin and Piano Series 7 Guitarre, Op. 45 No. 2 (arranged by Pablo de Sarasate) M. Moszkowski, 1920 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Carl Fischer Edition Compositions for Violin and Piano Select Pieces embracing the higher positions Hauser, H Op. 50 No 4 A. la Hongroise, 1902 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Carl Fischer's Music Library No. 271 Greig Op. 8 Sonata no.1 (in F) For Piano and Violin (Rud. Ganz and Theo Spiering), 1917 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Carl Fischer's Music Library No. 786 Grieg Op. 45 Sonata No. 3 (in C minor) for Piano and Violin (Rud. Ganz and Theo. Spiering), 1917 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Leopold Auer Concert Transcriptions Violin and Piano Melodie (Tschaikowsky, Op. 42, No. 3) (3315), 1921 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Collection Litolff No. 2111a Mozart 12 Duos pour 2 Violons Op. 70 Cahier 1 (No. 1-4), undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Carl Fischer's Music Library No. 876 Handel Sonata No. 6 (in E) Violin and Piano (I. Auer and Carl Friedberg), 1919 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Melody by Brigadier General Charles G. Dawes Violin and Piano As Played by Fritz Kreisler, 1921 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Carl Fischer's Music Library No. 364 L. v. Beethoven Two Romances for Violin and Piano (Edmund Singer), 1904 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Fritz Kreisler Classical Manuscripts Violin and Piano 10. Alt-Wiener Tanzweisen: No. 1 Liebesfreud, 1910 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Carl Fischer's Theatre Orchestra Edition Bridal Chorus from "Lohengrin" Richard Wagner arr. By J. Louis von der Mehden, Jr., 1910 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Fritz Kreisler Transcriptions for Violin and Piano Franz Schubert Ballet Music from "Rosamunde", 1917 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Fritz Kreisler Transcriptions for Piano and Violin N. Rimsky-Korsakow Two Sketches from "Scheherazade" No. 1 Danse Orientale, 1922 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Modern Concert Solos for Violin with Piano Havanaise Edited by Theodore Spiering C. saint Saens Op. 83, 1916 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Recital Music for Violin and Piano Series II Menuet and Trio in D, 1910 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Schimer's Library Vol. 356 Vieuxtemps Ballade et Polonaise De Concert Op. 38 (Violin and Piano) (Schradieck), 1895 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Favorite Recital Colos for the Violin with Piano Accompaniment Series I J. Massenet Melodie, Elegie des Errinyes Op. 10, 1901 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Franz Kreisler Transcriptions for Violin and Piano N. Rimsky-Korsakow Chanson Indoue (Hindoo Chant) From the Opera "Sadko", 1919 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Fransquita (Serenade) by Franz Lehar transcribed for Violin and Piano by Fritz Kreisler, 1927 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - A. Eugene Gondolfo Canzonetta pour Violon avec accompagnement de Piano Op. 6, 1898 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Fritz Kreisler Classical Manuscripts Violin and Piano 14. Gaetano Pugnani Tempo di minuetto, 1911 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Fritz Kreisler Classical Manuscripts Violin and Piano 2. Padre Martini Andantino, 1910 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - From Mischa Elman's Programme Selected Works of famous Composers for Violin and Piano Ludwig von Beethoven Menuet No. 2 in G, 1909 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Humoreske von Anton Dvorak Op. 101 No. 7 d) Fur Pianoforte und Violine von Fabian Rehfeld, 1894 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - David Hochstein Original Compositions and Concert transcriptions for Violin and Piano Waltz in A Major (Original Ab Major), 1916 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Dvorak Kreisler 1. Indian Lament, G Minor Indianisches Lamento, G Moll, 1914 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Schirmer's Library of Musical Classics Vol. 418 Franz Ries Op. 34 Suite No. 3 In G for Violin and Piano (Schradieck), 1898 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Schirmer's Library of Musical Classics Vol. 1235 Franck Sonata for Violin and Piano (Lichtenberg), 1915 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Masterpieces for Violin and Piano Svendsen, Joh. S. Op. 26 Romance, 1897 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Claude Debussy En Buteau (In a Sailboat) Extrait de la Petite Suite Violon et Piano, 1906 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Fritz Kreisler Transcriptions for Violin and Piano E. Granados Spanish Dance, 1915 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Carl Fischer Edition Violin and Piano Music In 1st and 3rd Positions C. Saint-Saens Le Cygne (The Swan) Mon coeur s'ouvere a ta voix, Cantabile from Samson et Dalila, 1894 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Tchaikovsky-Grunes Valse Sentimentale Op. 51, No. 6 Violin and Piano, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Albert Spalding Original Works-transcriptions Violin and Piano Wiegenlied (Cradle Song) Brahms (B 2213), 1930 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - To a Wild Rose (Edward MacDowell) Transcription for Violin and Pianoforte by Arthur Hartman Original Edition, 1907 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Fritz Kreisler Transcriptions for Violin and Piano E. Poldini Dancing Doll poupee Valsante, 1924 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Thais de J. Massenet Transcriptions pour Piano Seul et Instruments Divers Comedie Lyrique en 3 Actes I Meditation di Violin and Piano, 1894 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Fritz Kreisler Transcriptions for Violin and Piano P. Tschaikowsky Chansons Sans Paroles Song Without Words, 1924 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Concert and Exhibition Pieces for Violin and Piano Tivadar Nachez Op. 14 Danses Tziganes (Gypsy Dances) No. 1, 1910 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Masterpieces for Violin and Piano Series I Hungarian Dance No. 5 Joh. Brahms Arranged by Joseph Joachim, 1903 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Fritz Kreisler Transcripts for Violin and Piano R. Heuberger Midnight Bells (Viennese Melody) From "The Opera Ball", 1923 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Claude Debussy La fille aux Cheveux de lin (The Girl with the Flaxen Hair) Transcription pour Violon et Piano par Arthur Hartmann, 1910 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Fritz Kreisler Classical Manuscripts Violin and Piano 7. K. v. Ditterdorf Scherzo, 1910 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Arioso by Johann Sebastian Bach Transcribed for Violin and Piano by Sam Franko, 1915 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Masterpieces for Violin and Piano Series I Celebrated Air on the G String J. S. Bach (Arranged by August Wilhelmj), 1912 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Carl Fischer Edition Compositions for Violin and Piano Select Pieces embracing the higher positions Series I Drdla, Franz Souvenir, 1906 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Fritz Kreisler Classical Manuscripts Violin and Piano 4. Louis Couperin La Precieuse, 1910 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Masterpieces for Violin and Piano Series 6 Violin Solo from "The Violin Maker of Cremona" Jeno Hubay, 1909 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Fritz Kreisler Classical Manuscripts Violin and Piano 1. Louis Couperin Chanson Louis XIII and Pavane, 1910 (Box 5, Folder 49)